<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jest | JavaScript Without Grammar]]></title>
  <link href="http://browniefed.com/blog/categories/jest/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://browniefed.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-03T09:01:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://browniefed.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Brown]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating Ava to Jest]]></title>
    <link href="http://browniefed.com/blog/migrating-ava-to-jest/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-06T18:48:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://browniefed.com/blog/migrating-ava-to-jest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First off. Star the repo here <a href="https://github.com/facebook/jest">https://github.com/facebook/jest</a> so you can show some love for the hardwork that has been put into it.</p>

<h3>Props</h3>

<p>I was an early adopter of Jest back in the early days ( ~v0.4). It was okay but difficult to setup and slow with sometimes weird results and behaviors.</p>

<p>Tireless effort has been done by <a href="https://twitter.com/cpojer">Christoph Pojer</a> to get to the latest Jest (v16.01) so props to him and others working with him.</p>

<p>Check out the fantastic documentation here <a href="https://facebook.github.io/jest/docs/getting-started.html#content">https://facebook.github.io/jest/docs/getting-started.html</a></p>

<h3>Migrating in seconds</h3>

<p>There is almost nothing to write about on this topic because it was almost too easy.
Mostly because of <a href="https://github.com/skovhus/jest-codemods">jest-codemods</a>. It is a set of codemods crafted to transition your Tape or Ava project to Jest.</p>

<p>It is worth it. Jest has come along way when it comes to speed, functionality, configuration options, and ease of configuration (or lack there of to get started).</p>

<p>There were minor configurations I had to setup, but most were copying and pasting from the documentation.</p>

<p>Lets dive into the process real quick.</p>

<h3>First and last step to transition tests</h3>

<p>First install <code>jest-codemods</code></p>

<p><code>npm install -g jest-codemods</code></p>

<p>Then run <code>jest-codemods</code> in a desired directory.
It will prompt you with <code>Ava</code>, <code>Tape</code>, or a <code>both</code> option.
Then you provide a glob. I was running in my root so I provided the glob <code>**/__tests__/**/*.js</code> to convert all of my tests.</p>

<p>That was it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Done</h3>

<p>For basic implementations that is all you need!</p>

<p>Add <code>"test": "jest"</code> to your <code>package.json</code> <code>scripts</code> section and you&rsquo;re good to go!</p>

<h3>Caveats</h3>

<p>There are a few caveats to note.
In Ava you can pass in custom messages to the assertions. This is missing in the default <code>expect</code> provided by Jest but is by no means a deal breaker.</p>

<p><code>t.plan</code> and <code>t.skip</code> aren&rsquo;t supported by the codemod.</p>

<p><code>t.skip</code> and <code>t.plan</code> go hand-in-hand. I find <code>t.skip</code> to be somewhat unnecessary but <code>t.plan</code> is great for async tests.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t a deal breaker by any means. And Christopher is happy to accept a PR for it too!.</p>

<h3>What is awesome</h3>

<p> Our setup uses Webpack <code>root</code> property to use shared code across 2 directories in a monorepo. Adding that in other testing libraries required webpack and other NPM installed libraries.
 In Jest it is as simple as adding this to your config.</p>

<p>```
 &ldquo;modulePaths&rdquo;: [</p>

<pre><code>"/shared"
</code></pre>

<p>  ],
```</p>

<p>Are you using CSS Modules and want to actually test out certain classes get applied?
Well Jest has a nice out of the box solution. It does require an additional NPM install of <code>identity-obj-proxy</code> but it&rsquo;s worth when it&rsquo;s an easy config option.</p>

<p>```
&ldquo;moduleNameMapper&rdquo;: {</p>

<pre><code>"^.+\\.(css|less)$": "identity-obj-proxy"
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all you need to do to get CSS modules working.</p>

<p>For more awesome-examples and full configuration options checkout the documentation <a href="https://facebook.github.io/jest/docs/getting-started.html">https://facebook.github.io/jest/docs/getting-started.html</a>.
Many of the normal uses cases have been though of and are documented with copy and paste configuration options!</p>

<h3>Check it out</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m barely scratching the surface of what is great about Jest.
There is hopefully more coming but go use Jest, star the repo on git <a href="https://github.com/facebook/jest">https://github.com/facebook/jest</a> and never look back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
