<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: weather | JavaScript Without Grammar]]></title>
  <link href="http://browniefed.com/blog/categories/weather/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://browniefed.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-09T10:50:56-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://browniefed.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Brown]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create a Weather App with React Native]]></title>
    <link href="http://browniefed.com/blog/create-a-weather-app-with-react-native/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://browniefed.com/blog/create-a-weather-app-with-react-native</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Intro</h2>

<p>Weather apps are hot, and always heavily and over designed. Turns out you can just look outside&hellip; I digress. There is apparently an app called DarkSky that people rant and rave about, and they have an API they use called forecast.io. You can check out the API docs here <a href="https://developer.forecast.io/">https://developer.forecast.io/</a>.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll use forecast.io, so sign up for a developer account, and get your API key.</p>

<p>The development of this app was originally intended for a Chicktech workshop. I decided to turn it into a blog post as well just in case anyone wants to follow along.</p>

<p>You can look at all the code here <a href="https://github.com/browniefed/forecast">https://github.com/browniefed/forecast</a>. Each commit is an evolution of the previous code base and each line is commented.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t implement any data flow like redux because that&rsquo;d be overkill. This will work for both iOS and Android. We will focus on some slight React basics, but I am assuming you know a little JavaScript and have hopefully done a little React.</p>

<p>Also checkout <a href="https://github.com/catalinmiron/react-native-weather-app">https://github.com/catalinmiron/react-native-weather-app</a> which uses a weather icon font!</p>

<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>Hopefully you have Android/iOS running for React Native and can at least get a basic project working. If you don&rsquo;t then follow the instructions here <a href="http://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/getting-started.html">http://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/getting-started.html</a>.</p>

<h2>Start</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
